Guide to the Natalie L. M. Petesch Papers, 1940-2006 SC.2006.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Natalie L. M. Petesch Papers
1940-2006
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Petesch, Natalie L. M.
SC.2006.01
21 Linear Feet (61 document boxes)
Natalie L.M. Petesch was a local author and longtime Pittsburgh resident who made significant contributions to the local literary scene. She became a prolific author of short stories and novels. Her manuscript collection includes a large number of drafts and notes that document her writing and publishing career, as well as a smaller amount of material that documents her life as a public figure.
Biography
Natalie Levin Maines Petesch was a prolific author of primarily short fiction who was born to Polish-Russian immigrants in Detroit, Michigan, in 1924. Her mother died illiterate at the age of 35, an event that would shape Petesch's life as an author. As a young woman, she completed three novels, all of which remain unpublished to this day, before beginning work on her undergraduate degree. She earned a B.A. from Boston University, an M.A. in creative writing from Brandeis University, and a Ph.D. in English from the University of Texas at Austin, where she also met her second husband, author Donald Petesch. The two moved to Pittsburgh during the 1960s, and it was there that Petesch began in earnest her career as a fiction author.
After the publication of several short stories in periodicals beginning in 1964, a feminist press released her first novel, The Odyssey of Katinou Kalokovich, in 1974. That same year she received the Iowa Short Fiction Award for her collection After the First Death There is No Other. Petesch would go on to publish two more novels and six more short story collections, in addition to maintaining a presence in a number of prestigous literary magazines throughout the 1970s, '80s, and '90s. The 1996 collection The Immigrant Train and Other Stories was inspired by Petesch's upbringing as well as her observations of the Polish-American community in Pittsburgh.
Scope and Content Notes
The items in this collection document Natalie Petesch's life as an author, with emphasis on her writing career and status as a public figure in the Pittsburgh community. Approximately half of the collection consists of drafts, manuscripts, notes, and research materials that supported her writing process and that document the development of various projects. The Manuscripts and Related Materials series and the Notebooks series both serve this function, though their formats are distinctive. Other series document Petesch's role in public life (including cassette tapes, found in Series VII. Multimedia, that record public readings and interviews); her higher education in the field of literature; and the publication of her short stories in various serials and anthologies. Though much of her writing was highly personal, less of the collection's emphasis is placed on Petesch's private life. The majority of this material can be found in the Correspondence series in the form of letters she wrote to family and friends. This series may also overlap with other areas of the collection, as in the case of correspondence with publishers, which can also be found in Series I and IV, and copies of manuscripts and story ideas exchanged with friends.
At the time of processing, some large chunks were relocated within the collection to reside alongside related material. Petesch's own file groupings and titles have been retained wherever possible. Further information about arrangement can be found at the series level. Overall, this collection provides a unique, detailed glimpse into the writing process and web of relationships that inspired a member of the Pittsburgh community to make significant contributions to the local arts and letters.
Related Material
Copies of some of Petesch's published works, including serial publications, are held by the Special Collections department and may also be found in the general collections of the University Library System.
The following is a bibliography of Petesch's published monographs.
After the First Death There is No Other. Iowa City: University of Iowa Press, 1974.
The Confessions of Senora Francesca Navarro and Other Stories. Athens: Swallow Press/Ohio University Press, 2005.
Duncan's Colony. Athens: Swallow Press/Ohio University Press, 1982.
Flowering Mimosa. Athens: Swallow Press/Ohio University Press, 1987.
The Immigrant Train and Other Stories. Athens: Swallow Press/Ohio University Press, 1996.
Justina of Andalusia and Other Stories. Athens: Swallow Press/Ohio University Press, 1990.
The Odyssey of Katinou Kalokovich: A Novel. Tampa, Fla.: United Sisters, 1974.
Seasons Such as These: Two Novels. Chicago: Swallow Press, 1978.
Soul Clap its Hands and Sing: Stories. Boston: South End Press, 1981.
Wild With All Regret. Norcross, GA: Swallow's Tale Press, 1986.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Natalie L. M. Petesch on January 27, 2006.
Previous Citation
Natalie L. M. Petesch Papers, 1940-2006, SC.2006.01, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into the following seven series.
I. Manuscripts and Related Materials, 1940-2006
II. Notebooks, 1964-1986
III. Correspondence, 1947-2006
IV. Publicity, 1950-1999
V. Education, 1952-1962
VI. Offprints, 1964-1998
VII. Multimedia, 1955-1998
Sound recordings; Clippings (Information artifacts); Notebooks; Correspondence; Manuscripts for publication; Women authors, American -- 20th century; Jewish women authors; American literature -- Jewish authors; American literature -- Polish American authors; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Fiction; Feminist literature; Immigrants -- United States -- Social life and customs -- Fiction; Polish Americans -- Social life and customs -- Fiction; Poland -- Emigration and immigration -- Fiction; Short stories, American; Pittsburgh (Pa.); Detroit (Mich.); Literary prizes -- Iowa; University of Texas at Austin; Ohio University. Press; Ray, David; Maines, Rachel; Petesch, Donald A.; Petesch, Natalie L. M.
- Manuscripts and Related Materials, 1940-2005; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series, which comprises the bulk of the collection, documents Petesch's writing process and the development of both her projects and her authorial identity. Documentation ranges from extensive research materials used for her novels and story collections, to the 1964 typescript of the first short story she ever published. There are also drafts and manuscripts from an abundance of unpublished works, including the three novels she wrote during the 1940s and 1950s.
  The first three subseries are dedicated to her three most recently published story collections because the documentation surrounding these works, particularly the research and drafting processes, is particularly extensive. Works whose inception was less thoroughly documented are grouped into subseries of long-form works, i.e. novels and story collections, and shorter works such as stories and essays. These latter subseries are arranged alphabetically by work. In the case of longer short story collections, drafts and notes pertaining to constituent stories are grouped together alongside materials related to the work as a whole.
  Materials likely to be found in all of these subseries include what Petesch referred to as "fowle papers"--groupings of miscellaneous notes, ideas, outlines, research materials, and fragmented drafts created in the early stages of authorship. More organized research materials, including notes, annotated photocopies of source materials, correspondence with other authors and research institutions, and maps and brochures from research trips are also present along with many typescript drafts and revision notes. It is possible that manuscript versions may be duplicated; Petesch described copies of her works variously as "perfect," "original," "complete," or "final," and only detailed comparison would reveal whether each copy is unique.
  - The Confessions of Senora Francesca Navarro and Other Stories, 1995-2005; 1.
    - Page Proofs and Copy Edited Manuscripts of Confessions (1/3) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Page Proofs and Copy Edited Manuscripts of Confessions (2/3) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Page Proofs and Copy Edited Manuscripts of Confessions (3/3) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Red-Lined Copy of Confessions as Sent to Nancy Basmajian (copy 1/2) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Red-Lined Copy of Confessions as sent to Nancy Basmajian (Copy 2/2) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Editing Notes and Correspondence with Nancy Basmajian of Swallow Press re:Confessions (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Author's Final Copy of The Confessions of Senora Francesca Navarro and Other Stories (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Los Cien Ultimos Dias de la Republica by Jose Manuel Martinez Bande (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - The Passionate War by Peter Wyden (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Prisoners of the Good Fight by Carl Geiser (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - They Shall Not Pass by Dolores Ibarruri (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - The Civil War in Spain by Raymond Carr (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Men in Battle by Alvah Bessie (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Speeches and Articles by Dolores Ibarruri (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - The Spanish Civil War by David Mitchell (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Clippings and Quotes on the Spanish Civil War, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - New Mexico File, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - La Muerte de Esperanza by Eduardo de Guzman (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Drafts and Notes for Acknowledgments/Dedication/Epigraph for Confessions (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - The Siege of the Alcazar by Cecil D. Eby (Notes) (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - The Siege of the Alcazar by Cecil D. Eby (Annotated Photocopies) (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - First Draft of "This Passionate Sun" (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Fowle Papers for "This Passionate Sun" (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Notecards Used in Writing "Confessions" (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Notecards Used in Writing "Timoteo" (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Notecards re: Alcazor (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Notecards for "This Passionate Sun" (1/2) (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Notecards for "This Passionate Sun" (2/2) (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Preparatory Notes for "This Passionate Sun" (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Fowle Papers for "Federico at the Clinico" (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Typescript of "Timoteo" (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - "The Hand of St. Teresa" (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - "Federico at the Clinico" Extra Sheets/Copies (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Archetype and Corrected Typescript of "The Hand of St. Teresa" (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Xerox Copy of the Archetype of "Federico at the Clinico" (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - The Life of St. Teresa of Jesus of the Order of Our Lady of Carmel, Written By Herself (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - 5x8 Cards Used for "Teresa" (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Original of "The Hand of St. Teresa" (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Fowle Papers for "Teresa" (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Fowle Papers for "Timoteo, the Derelicto" (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - First Draft of "Confessions" (1/2) (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - First Draft of "Confessions" (2/2) (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Scraps of Fowle Papers for "Confessions" (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Fowle Papers for "The Diary of the Siege of the Alcazor" (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Original Typescript of "Confessions" (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Original Typescript of "Timoteo, the Derelicto" (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Corrections to "Confessions" (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - "Federico" and "Timoteo" Returned from Gettysburg Review, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Perfect Copies of "Federico" (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Perfect Copy of "Timoteo", 2003 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Perfect Copy of "Teresa" as Submitted Anonymously to Contests (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Material Deleted from "This Passionate Sun" (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Perfect Photocopies of "Teresa" and "Federico" Addressed to The Gettysburg Review, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Original Version of "This Passionate Sun" (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Perfect Copy of "This Passionate Sun" (Long Version), 2003 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Copy of "Timoteo, the Derelicto" as Appearing in The Chariton Review, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Revised Version of "This Passionate Sun" with Final Publishable Copy (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Typescript of Revisions to "This Passionate Sun" (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Final As-Published Manuscript of The Confessions of Senora Francesca Navarro (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Title Page and Acknolwedgments for This Passionate Sun as Prepared for Typist (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Corrections to Typescript of "This Passionate Sun" (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Perfect Copy of "The Hand of St. Teresa" (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Complete Manuscript of "The Confessions of Senora Francesca Navarro" Before Cuts Made for Publication (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Ideas, Titles, Epigraphs (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - La Perfecta Casada by Fray Luis de Leon (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Original Typescript of "The Confessions of Senora Francesca Navarro" (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Espana Heroica by General Vincente Rojo (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - A Concise History of the Spanish Civil War by Gabriel Jackson (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - The Spanish Civil War by Hugh Thomas (1/2) (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - The Spanish Civil War by Hugh Thomas (2/2) (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - The Passionate War by Peter Wyden (Ideas, Titles, Epigraphs) (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - The Civil War in Spain by Raymond Carr (Ideas, Titles, Epigraphs) (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - La Muerte de la Esperanza by Eduardo de Guzman (Ideas, Titles, Epigraphs) (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Photocopies from Rosenstone's Crusade of the Left (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Men in Battle by Alvah Bessie (Ideas, Titles, Epigraphs) (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Calendar of Events from Geiser, Bessie, Mattarranz (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Behind the Spanish Mask by Lawrence Dundas (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - The Spanish Civil War by Hugh Thomas (Ideas, Titles, Epigraphs) (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Prisoners of the Good Fight by Carl Geiser (Ideas, Epigraphs, Titles) (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Original Typescript of "This Passionate Sun" (Photocopy) (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Manuscrito de un Superviviente by Felipe Mattarrenz Gonzalez (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Editing Questions for "Federico", 2002 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Crusade of the Left by Robert Rosenstone (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - The Spanish Cockpit by Franz Borkenau (Ideas, Epigraphs, Titles) (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - The Spanish Civil War by David Mitchel (Ideas, Epigraphs, Titles) (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Original Version of "This Passionate Sun" (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Research Bibliography on the Spanish Civil War, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Memo on the "Law of Responsibilities" (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Chart of Possible Stories for Spain Collection (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Maps of Spain (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Names File (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Acknowledgments/Epigraphs (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - List of Books Read for Confessions (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Meditations by Marcus Aurelius (Notes from 1945 George Long Translation) (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Bibliography of Books Already Read (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Bibliography on the Spanish Civil War (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Bibliographic Material for Confessions (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - The Civil War in Alicante by Vincente Ramos (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - The Poems of St. John of the Cross, trans. William Barnstone (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Place Names for Madrid (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - File of Books in Spanish on the Spanish Civil War (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Maps of Cities in Spain (1/3) (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Maps of Cities in Spain (2/3) (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Maps of Cities in Spain (3/3) (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Maps from Peter Wyden's The Passionate War (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - The Spanish Cockpit by Franz Borkenau (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Possible Magazines for Fiction Submissions (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - The Immigrant Train and Other Stories, 1970-1996; 2.
    - Material from Ed Nizalowski, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Poles in America by Paul Fox and Cambridge History of Russian Poland by Halek Zaretsky (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Laughing in the Jungle by Lois Adamic (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Destination America by Maldwyn Jones (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Hungry Hearts by Anzia Yezierska (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Waters Under the Earth by Martha Ostenso (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - A Nation of Nations, ed. Peter Marzio (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - American Mosaic by Joan Morrison and Charlotte Fox Zabusky (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Letters from the Promised Land, ed. Harold Barton (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Island of Hope, Island of Tears by David Brownstone, Douglass Brownstone, and Irene Franck (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Material for Pittsburgh Stories (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - From Alien to Citizen by E.A. Steiner (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Early Beginnings of Immigrant Project, 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Material from the Immigration History Research Center, 1991-1992 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Social Religion by Scott Nearing (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Materials for Another Pittsburgh Story (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - American Immigrant Women by Cecyle Neidle (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - This Was America by Oscar Handlin (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - The Russian Immigrant by Jerome Davis (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - The Rebel Girl by Elizabeth Surley Flynn (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Pittsburgh (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - After Bread by Henryk Sienkiewicz (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - The Peasants by Ladislas Reymont (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - A Footnote to Folly by Mary Heaton Vorst (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - The New Immigration by Peter Roberts (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - File for a Possible "Western" Story of Immigrants (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Notes from WQED Program "The Polish Americans" (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Child Labor in City Streets by Edward Clopper (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Land of Their Choice by Theodore Blegen (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Pictorial History of Immigration by Oscar Handlin (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - "Immigration to the Southern States" by Walter Fleming in Political Science Quarterly (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - The Old World in the New by Edward Alsworth Ross (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - America's Polish Heritage by Joseph Wytral (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Barbarous Mexico by John Kenneth Turner (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Strangers at the Door by Ann Novotny (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - In the Shadow of Liberty by Edward Corsi (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - The Great Coalfield War by George S. McGovern (used for "The Way We Lived Then") (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Intention/Notes for Immigrant Train (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Gateway to Liberty by Mary Shapiro (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Hamtramck Then and Now by Arthur Evans Wood (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Old World Traits Transplanted by Robert Park & Herbert Miller and First Generation by June Namias (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Plain Folk, ed. David Katzman and William Tuttle (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - The New Americans by Cecyle Neidle (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Ellis Island File for Planned Novel on Petesch's Mother, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - The Polish Peasant in Europe and America by William Thomas and Florian Znanecki (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Life Record of an Immigrant by William Thomas and Florian Znaniecki (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Polish Names Collected for Immigrant Train (1/2) (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Polish Names Collected for Immigrant Train (2/2) (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Unused Dedication of Immigrant Train to Petesch's Mother (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Bibliographies Collected for Immigrant Train (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Maps and Photos for Immigrant Train (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Calendar of Important Dates for Immigrant Train (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - On the Trail of the Immigrant by Edward Steiner (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Spiral Notebook from Trip to Ellis Island, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Notes and Clippings on Florida Migrant Workers, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Clippings on Texas, 1970-1971 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Notes on Fish, Birds, and Sea Shells for Immigrant Train (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Issues of Spectrum from the Immigration History Resource Center, 1975-1988 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Maps and Brochures from Minneapolis and St. Paul, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Materials Received from the Immigration History Resource Center, St. Paul, MN, 1992-1996 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Various Communications from IHRC (Newsletters, etc.), 1991-1993 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Flyers from IHRC (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Path Breaking by Abigail Scott Dunaway (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - The Making of an American by Jacob Riis (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - The Passing of the Great Race by Madison Grant (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Railroad Maps and Itineraries of Immigrants ca. 1900-1914 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - The Gospel of Wealth by Andrew Carnegie (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Autobiography of Andrew Carnegie, ed. Louise Whitfield Carnegie (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Materials from the Immigration History Resource Center, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Notes and Bibliography from the Immigration History Resource Center (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - The Dangerous Classes of New York by Charles Loring Brace (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - The Destiny of Europe's Gypsies by Donald Kendrick and Gratta Paxon (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - The Gypsies in Poland: History and Customs by Jerzy Ficowski (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Poles in America by Joseph Wytrwal (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Women at Work: Autobiography of Mary Anderson (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - The Russian Peasant by Howard Kennard (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - They Chose Minnesota: A Survey of the State's Ethnic Groups, ed. June Drenning Holmquist (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Notes on Tenements in New York City (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Notes on Polish Proverbs and Rituals, Especially at Easter (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - We Were There: The Story of Working Women in America by Barbara Meyer Wertheimer (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Legacy of the Ludlow Massacre by H.M. Gitelman (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - The Lever of Riches: Farming Systems in Poland by Joel Mokyr (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Andrew Carnegie's "The Gospel of Wealth" and Other Timely Essays by Edward C. Kirkland (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Thomas and Znaniecki's The Polish Peasant (1/2) (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Thomas and Znaniecki's The Polish Peasant (2/2) (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - The Life of Bees by Maurice Maeterlink (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Bees: The Golden Legend by Edwin Way Teale (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Phillips'Beekeeping (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - How to Keep Bees by Anna Comstock (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Suggested Artwork for Immigrant Train (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Edited Page Proofs of Immigrant Train (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - "Cousin Ludwika" (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - "The Way We Lived Then" (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - "Czesio" Page Proofs (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Dedication and Epigraph for Immigrant Train (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - "Stefan Zarenski" (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - "God's Place" (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Complete Edited Version of Immigrant Train (1/2) (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Complete Edited Version of Immigrant Train (2/2) (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Photos and Maps Used for Immigrant Train (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Clippings for Immigrant Train (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Lists of Polish Names and Organizations (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Material from the National Immigration Forum, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Complete and Perfect Original Manuscript of Immigrant Train (1/2), 1995 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Complete and Perfect Original Manuscript of Immigrant Train (2/2) (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Notes for "The Orphan Train" (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Fowle Papers for "Cousin Ludwika", 1995 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Handwritten Original of "Pawel" (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Archetype of "Pawel Czamocki"/"Pawel in America" (Box 16, Folder 3)